<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Mikedev website</title><link>https://michedev.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Mikedev website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://michedev.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mathematical Details of Noise Injection in Diffusion Models</title><link>https://michedev.github.io/posts/ddpm_noising_extensive_formulation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michedev.github.io/posts/ddpm_noising_extensive_formulation/</guid><description>Diffusion process Let $X_0$ the input image, the goal of the diffusion process is to gradually add noise to the image until its pixel values approximate a standard normal distribution. This enables a neural network to be trained to reverse the diffusion process and reconstruct the original image from the noised image. In this post, we will focus on the mathematical details behind the noise injection step of the diffusion process.</description></item><item><title>The stranger of Albert Camus</title><link>https://michedev.github.io/posts/the_stranger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michedev.github.io/posts/the_stranger/</guid><description>Introduction Two weeks ago I decided to read the book &amp;ldquo;The stranger&amp;rdquo; by Albert Camus. I was so impressed by the book that I thought about that for days and wrote an analysis of the book&amp;rsquo;s narrative and characters on my own. Now, I&amp;rsquo;m here to share my thoughts with everyone
Part 1, an introspective journey Part 1 is self-centered on the protagonist&amp;rsquo;s actions, with a strong introspective focus to understand him and his thought process, while the second part is more about how Mersault&amp;rsquo;s actions are judged by the others.</description></item></channel></rss>